EZRA SINGH

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Bringing more than 8 years of experience leading website design projects, including gathering user requirements, producing code, creating mockups and enhancing designs. Focused on creating clean, robust code with exceptional security. Achieves compatibility targets while meeting and exceeding customer demands.

SKILLS

- Gathering Requirements
- Best Practices and Standards
- Continuous Integration
 Systems
- Performance and Scalability Optimization
- Application Development
- Code Review
- Complex Problem-Solving
- Critical Thinking
- Algorithmic Thinking
- Technical Requirements Analysis
- Web Architecture
- Graphic and User Interface Design
- Distributed Technologies

WORK HISTORY

LEAD FULLSTACK ENGINEER 07/2020 to 10/2023

Mongotel, Brooklyn, NY

- Checked client code for bugs and weaknesses using approved troubleshooting methods.
- Revised, modularized and updated old code bases to modern development standards, reducing operating costs and improving functionality.
- Worked with project managers, developers, quality assurance and customers to resolve technical issues.
- Designed system architecture and implemented product specifications in collaboration with team members and subject matter experts, ensuring seamless code development.
- Collaborated with domain experts to understand and characterize products and identify problematic issues.
- Documented software design, detected faults, project planning discrepancies and other vital data.

CODING INSTRUCTOR 01/2019 to 03/2020

Dream Big Foundation, Brooklyn, NY

- Designed classes on App Development for students.
- Emphasized web etiquette and practical applications of technology for professional use.
- Tested and evaluated student progress to determine effectiveness and impact of teaching methods, materials and projects.
- Used lectures, demonstrations and discussions to instruct students individually and in small groups.

FRONTEND DEVELOPER 01/2018 to 01/2019

Related Painting, New York, NY

- Planned website development, converting mockups into usable web presence with HTML, lavaScript, AlAX and React.
- Conducted testing and review of website design for responsiveness, clarity and effectiveness.
- Conducted functional testing over the course of web development lifecycle.
- Discussed site and app requirements with clients to produce actionable development plans and budgets.
- Ran debugging tools such as Firebug and Chrome Inspector to eliminate flaws and glitches prior to publishing.

CLOUD CONSULTANT 08/2017 to 01/2018

Law Office Of Stephanie DiPietro, P.C, New York, NY

- Identified and remediated single points of failure and security risks.
- Researched and understood emerging technologies and end-user needs.
- Recommended design changes to production systems in response to changing business process, capacity, risks and performance requirements.
- Provided solution designs to meet system strategies, capabilities and technologies and to respond to current and future business requirements.

AUTOMATION TEST ENGINEER 07/2016 to 07/2017

Placemeter, New York, NY

- Documented testing procedures for developers and future testing use.
- Debugged code and located root causes of problems by reviewing configuration files and logs.
- Reduced overall testing hours 80% by writing and optimizing automation test scripts in Python.
- Installed, configured, tested and maintained operating systems, application software and system management tools.

WEB DEVELOPER 01/2016 to 07/2017

Empire Capital Holdings, New York, NY

- Coded websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- Provided front-end website development using WordPress, Hubspot and other editing software.
- Oversaw back-end development using PHP to maintain website integrity, security and efficiency.
- Converted graphic designs to usable web images using Adobe Photoshop.
- Developed technical solutions required to accommodate specific user-facing assets such as Property Search Engine.

SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR 01/2016 to 07/2017

Venture Capital Properties, New York, NY

- Installed important security and functionality patches to maintain optimal protections against intrusion and system reliability.
- Provisioned new software and hardware for use according to internal business and security policies.
- Completed reports detailing network and systems performance, costs and downtime issues.
- Spearheaded inventory control measures to replenish and maintain IT equipment, supplies, tools and replacement parts.
- Oversaw IT activities to maintain operations by maintaining laptops, tablets and PDAs for ~100 users.
- Introduced cloud infrastructure and management tools to create and manage virtual server computing environments.

HELP DESK SUPPORT 06/2015 to 12/2015

Rochester Institute Of Technology, RIT, Rochester, NY

- Configured hardware, devices and software to set up work stations for employees.
- Removed malware, ransomware and other threats from laptops and desktop systems.
- Responded to inquiries by phone, email and walk-up requests.
- Logged activities in tracking systems to maintain accurate, timely records.
- Used established procedures to identify critical customer and system issues and escalate problems to appropriate people or groups.
- Installed new desktop systems and migrated data to new machines.

DEVELOPMENT SKILLS

Technical Skills

- Git
- Debian GNU/Linux
- Docker
- Kubernetes
- Terraform
- Traefik / Nginx / Apache
- Bash
- SQL
- AWS, FlyIO
- Jira
- Github, Gitlab
- OAuth2, OIDC
- Netlify, Heroku, Vercel

Client Side Skills

- HTML, Jinja, Pug
- CSS, SCSS, LESS
- Javascript (ES5, ES6)
- Webpack, Vite
- NodeJS, Typescript
- Long-Polling, Server-Side Events, WebSockets
- API Consumption (REST or GraphQL)
- WebAssembly

Frontend Frameworks

- TailwindCSS, Bulma, Bootstrap
- ThreeJS, React Three Fiber
- React, Redux (Saga, Thunk), Zustand
- SocketIO
- jQuery

Server Side Skills

- Rust
- Python
- PHP
- Redis
- MySQL, PostgreSQL
- MongoDB
- API Implementation (REST or GraphQL)
- End-to-End Integration Testing

Backend Frameworks

- NextJS, ExpressJS
- Django
- Flask
- Axum
- TemporalIO
- OpenAPI
- Ory (Kratos, Keto, Hydra)
- Auth0

OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS

- Contributor to NixOS
- Contributor to OpenAPI
- Author of ACPI Event Manager

EDUCATION

High School of Art And Design, New York, NY

Illustration, 05/2015

- Adobe Certified Associate (May 2015)
- NOCTI Certified: Visual Arts